<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<fpdoc-descriptions>
<package name="fcl">

<!--
  ====================================================================
    custweb
  ====================================================================
-->

<module name="CustWeb">
<short>Base functionality for HTTP hosting implementations</short>
<descr>
<p>The <var>custweb</var> unit provides the base functionality common to all HTTP hosting implementations in Free Pascal: CGI, FastCGI, HTTP server and Apache loadable modules.
It contains the foundational classes <link id="TWebHandler">TWebHandler</link> and <link id="TCustomWebApplication">TCustomWebApplication</link> that handle HTTP requests and provide web application functionality.</p>
<p>The unit supports module-based request handling, error management, event logging, and various configuration options for different hosting environments.
It provides the infrastructure for routing requests to appropriate HTTP modules and managing the complete request-response cycle.</p>
</descr>

<!-- uses unit Visibility: default -->
<element name="CustApp">
<short>Custom application framework classes</short>
</element>

<!-- uses unit Visibility: default -->
<element name="Classes">
<short>Basic component and persistence classes</short>
</element>

<!-- uses unit Visibility: default -->
<element name="SysUtils">
<short>System utility functions and classes</short>
</element>

<!-- uses unit Visibility: default -->
<element name="httpdefs">
<short>HTTP protocol definitions and constants</short>
</element>

<!-- uses unit Visibility: default -->
<element name="fphttp">
<short>HTTP request and response handling classes</short>
</element>

<!-- uses unit Visibility: default -->
<element name="eventlog">
<short>System event logging functionality</short>
</element>

<!-- procedure type Visibility: default -->
<element name="TGetModuleEvent">
<short>Event type for determining HTTP module class for a request</short>
<descr>
<p>Event handler type called when the web application needs to determine which HTTP module class to use for handling a specific request.
This allows custom logic for module selection based on request properties.</p>
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="TWebHandler.OnGetModule">TWebHandler.OnGetModule</link>
</seealso>
</element>

<!-- argument Visibility: default -->
<element name="TGetModuleEvent.Sender">
<short>The web handler object that triggered the event</short>
</element>

<!-- argument Visibility: default -->
<element name="TGetModuleEvent.ARequest">
<short>The HTTP request being processed</short>
</element>

<!-- argument Visibility: default -->
<element name="TGetModuleEvent.ModuleClass">
<short>Variable to store the selected HTTP module class</short>
</element>

<!-- procedure type Visibility: default -->
<element name="TOnShowRequestException">
<short>Event type for custom exception handling in HTTP requests</short>
<descr>
<p>Event handler type called when an exception occurs during HTTP request processing.
Allows custom handling of exceptions before the default error response is generated.</p>
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="TWebHandler.OnShowRequestException">TWebHandler.OnShowRequestException</link>
</seealso>
</element>

<!-- argument Visibility: default -->
<element name="TOnShowRequestException.AResponse">
<short>The HTTP response object for sending error response</short>
</element>

<!-- argument Visibility: default -->
<element name="TOnShowRequestException.AnException">
<short>The exception that occurred during request processing</short>
</element>

<!-- argument Visibility: default -->
<element name="TOnShowRequestException.handled">
<short>Set to <var>True</var> if the exception was handled by the event</short>
</element>

<!-- procedure type Visibility: default -->
<element name="TLogEvent">
<short>Event type for logging web application events</short>
<descr>
<p>Event handler type called when the web application needs to log an event.
Allows custom logging implementation for web application events and errors.</p>
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="TWebHandler.OnLog">TWebHandler.OnLog</link>
</seealso>
</element>

<!-- argument Visibility: default -->
<element name="TLogEvent.EventType">
<short>The type of event being logged</short>
</element>

<!-- argument Visibility: default -->
<element name="TLogEvent.Msg">
<short>The message text to be logged</short>
</element>

<!-- procedure type Visibility: default -->
<element name="TInitModuleEvent">
<short>Event type for HTTP module initialization</short>
<descr>
<p>Event handler type called when an HTTP module is initialized before handling a request.
Allows custom initialization of module properties and setup.</p>
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="TWebHandler.OnInitModule">TWebHandler.OnInitModule</link>
</seealso>
</element>

<!-- argument Visibility: default -->
<element name="TInitModuleEvent.Sender">
<short>The web handler object that triggered the event</short>
</element>

<!-- argument Visibility: default -->
<element name="TInitModuleEvent.Module">
<short>The HTTP module being initialized</short>
</element>

<!-- class Visibility: default -->
<element name="TWebHandler">
<short>Base class for handling HTTP requests in web applications</short>
<descr>
<p><var>TWebHandler</var> is the core component that handles HTTP requests in web applications.
It provides the framework for routing requests to appropriate HTTP modules, handling errors, and managing the request-response cycle.
This class serves as the foundation for all HTTP hosting implementations including CGI, FastCGI, HTTP server and Apache modules.</p>
<p>The handler supports both legacy routing and new HTTP routing systems, module lifecycle management, error handling with custom exception display, and event logging.</p>
</descr>
<errors>
<p>May raise HTTP-related exceptions during request processing.</p>
</errors>
<seealso>
<link id="TCustomWebApplication">TCustomWebApplication</link>
</seealso>
</element>

<!-- constructor Visibility: public -->
<element name="TWebHandler.Create">
<short>Creates a new web handler instance</short>
<descr>
<p>Creates and initializes a new <var>TWebHandler</var> instance with default settings.
Sets up default module variable name, enables default module handling, and configures request handling options.</p>
</descr>
<errors>
<p>May raise exceptions during component initialization.</p>
</errors>
<seealso>
<link id="TWebHandler.Destroy">Destroy</link>
</seealso>
</element>

<!-- argument Visibility: default -->
<element name="TWebHandler.Create.AOwner">
<short>The owner component for the web handler</short>
</element>

<!-- destructor Visibility: public -->
<element name="TWebHandler.Destroy">
<short>Destroys the web handler instance</short>
<descr>
<p>Cleans up resources and destroys the <var>TWebHandler</var> instance.
Resets module factory event handlers and performs standard component cleanup.</p>
</descr>
<errors>
<p>No specific errors expected during destruction.</p>
</errors>
<seealso>
<link id="TWebHandler.Create">Create</link>
</seealso>
</element>

<!-- procedure Visibility: public -->
<element name="TWebHandler.Run">
<short>Main request processing loop for the web handler</short>
<descr>
<p>Starts the main request processing loop that waits for incoming HTTP requests and handles them.
Continues processing until the handler is terminated, calling idle events between requests when available.</p>
</descr>
<errors>
<p>May raise exceptions during request waiting or processing.</p>
</errors>
<seealso>
<link id="TWebHandler.DoHandleRequest">DoHandleRequest</link>
<link id="TWebHandler.OnIdle">OnIdle</link>
</seealso>
</element>

<!-- procedure Visibility: public -->
<element name="TWebHandler.Log">
<short>Logs an event message using the configured log handler</short>
<descr>
<p>Logs an event message with the specified event type if a log event handler is assigned.
Provides centralized logging for web application events and errors.</p>
</descr>
<errors>
<p>No specific errors, depends on log handler implementation.</p>
</errors>
<seealso>
<link id="TWebHandler.OnLog">OnLog</link>
</seealso>
</element>

<!-- argument Visibility: default -->
<element name="TWebHandler.Log.EventType">
<short>The type of event being logged</short>
</element>

<!-- argument Visibility: default -->
<element name="TWebHandler.Log.Msg">
<short>The message text to log</short>
</element>

<!-- procedure Visibility: public -->
<element name="TWebHandler.DoHandleRequest">
<short>Handles a complete HTTP request with error handling and cleanup</short>
<descr>
<p>Processes a complete HTTP request including error handling, response sending, and proper cleanup of request and response objects.
Ensures content is sent even if not explicitly sent by the handler, and logs any content sending errors.</p>
</descr>
<errors>
<p>Handles and logs content sending errors internally.</p>
</errors>
<seealso>
<link id="TWebHandler.HandleRequest">HandleRequest</link>
<link id="TWebHandler.EndRequest">EndRequest</link>
</seealso>
</element>

<!-- argument Visibility: default -->
<element name="TWebHandler.DoHandleRequest.ARequest">
<short>The HTTP request to process</short>
</element>

<!-- argument Visibility: default -->
<element name="TWebHandler.DoHandleRequest.AResponse">
<short>The HTTP response to send</short>
</element>

<!-- procedure Visibility: public -->
<element name="TWebHandler.HandleRequest">
<short>Routes and processes an HTTP request to the appropriate handler</short>
<descr>
<p>Routes an HTTP request to the appropriate handler using either legacy routing or the HTTP router system.
Catches and handles any exceptions that occur during request processing by calling the exception handler.</p>
</descr>
<errors>
<p>Catches all exceptions during request processing and handles them via <var>ShowRequestException</var>.</p>
</errors>
<seealso>
<link id="TWebHandler.LegacyRouting">LegacyRouting</link>
<link id="TWebHandler.ShowRequestException">ShowRequestException</link>
</seealso>
</element>

<!-- argument Visibility: default -->
<element name="TWebHandler.HandleRequest.ARequest">
<short>The HTTP request to route and process</short>
</element>

<!-- argument Visibility: default -->
<element name="TWebHandler.HandleRequest.AResponse">
<short>The HTTP response to populate</short>
</element>

<!-- property Visibility: public -->
<element name="TWebHandler.HandleGetOnPost">
<short>Controls whether GET requests are handled by POST handlers</short>
<descr>
<p>When <var>True</var>, allows POST request handlers to also process GET requests.
This provides flexibility for web applications that need to handle both request types with the same logic.</p>
</descr>
<seealso>
</seealso>
</element>

<!-- property Visibility: public -->
<element name="TWebHandler.RedirectOnError">
<short>Controls whether errors trigger HTTP redirects</short>
<descr>
<p>When <var>True</var>, exceptions during request processing cause an HTTP redirect to the URL specified in <link id="TWebHandler.RedirectOnErrorURL">RedirectOnErrorURL</link>.
When <var>False</var>, errors are displayed as HTML error pages.</p>
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="TWebHandler.RedirectOnErrorURL">RedirectOnErrorURL</link>
</seealso>
</element>

<!-- property Visibility: public -->
<element name="TWebHandler.RedirectOnErrorURL">
<short>URL template for error redirects</short>
<descr>
<p>Specifies the URL pattern used for error redirects when <link id="TWebHandler.RedirectOnError">RedirectOnError</link> is <var>True</var>.
The URL can contain format specifiers to include error message details in the redirect.</p>
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="TWebHandler.RedirectOnError">RedirectOnError</link>
</seealso>
</element>

<!-- property Visibility: public -->
<element name="TWebHandler.ApplicationURL">
<short>Base URL for the web application</short>
<descr>
<p>Specifies the base URL for the web application.
When empty, the application URL is determined from the request script name.
Used for constructing absolute URLs and setting module base URLs.</p>
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="TWebHandler.SetBaseURL">SetBaseURL</link>
</seealso>
</element>

<!-- property Visibility: public -->
<element name="TWebHandler.AllowDefaultModule">
<short>Controls whether requests without module names use default modules</short>
<descr>
<p>When <var>True</var>, requests that don't specify a module name will use the default module specified in <link id="TWebHandler.DefaultModuleName">DefaultModuleName</link>.
When <var>False</var>, requests without module names result in an error.</p>
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="TWebHandler.DefaultModuleName">DefaultModuleName</link>
</seealso>
</element>

<!-- property Visibility: public -->
<element name="TWebHandler.DefaultModuleName">
<short>Name of the default HTTP module for requests without explicit module names</short>
<descr>
<p>Specifies which HTTP module to use when a request doesn't explicitly specify a module name and <link id="TWebHandler.AllowDefaultModule">AllowDefaultModule</link> is <var>True</var>.
If empty and only one module is registered, that module becomes the default.</p>
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="TWebHandler.AllowDefaultModule">AllowDefaultModule</link>
</seealso>
</element>

<!-- property Visibility: public -->
<element name="TWebHandler.ModuleVariable">
<short>Query parameter name for specifying HTTP module names</short>
<descr>
<p>Specifies the name of the query parameter used to determine which HTTP module should handle a request.
Defaults to 'Module'. For example, '?Module=MyModule' would route to the MyModule HTTP module.</p>
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="TWebHandler.GetModuleName">GetModuleName</link>
</seealso>
</element>

<!-- property Visibility: public -->
<element name="TWebHandler.OnGetModule">
<short>Event for custom module selection logic</short>
<descr>
<p>Event called to determine which HTTP module class should handle a request.
Allows custom module selection logic based on request properties, overriding the default module name resolution.</p>
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="TGetModuleEvent">TGetModuleEvent</link>
</seealso>
</element>

<!-- property Visibility: public -->
<element name="TWebHandler.Email">
<short>Administrator email address for error notifications</short>
<descr>
<p>Email address displayed in error pages for user contact.
Used in HTML error pages to provide a contact point for error reporting.</p>
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="TWebHandler.Administrator">Administrator</link>
</seealso>
</element>

<!-- property Visibility: public -->
<element name="TWebHandler.Title">
<short>Application title displayed in error pages</short>
<descr>
<p>Title of the web application used in error page headers and titles.
Provides branding and identification in error responses.</p>
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="ExceptionToHTML">ExceptionToHTML</link>
</seealso>
</element>

<!-- property Visibility: public -->
<element name="TWebHandler.Administrator">
<short>Administrator name for error pages</short>
<descr>
<p>Name of the application administrator displayed in error pages.
Used together with the email address to provide contact information for error reporting.</p>
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="TWebHandler.Email">Email</link>
</seealso>
</element>

<!-- property Visibility: public -->
<element name="TWebHandler.OnShowRequestException">
<short>Event for custom exception handling during request processing</short>
<descr>
<p>Event called when an exception occurs during HTTP request processing.
Allows custom handling of exceptions before the default error response is generated.</p>
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="TOnShowRequestException">TOnShowRequestException</link>
</seealso>
</element>

<!-- property Visibility: public -->
<element name="TWebHandler.OnIdle">
<short>Event triggered when the handler is idle between requests</short>
<descr>
<p>Event called between request processing cycles when the handler is waiting for new requests.
Allows background processing or cleanup tasks during idle periods.</p>
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="TWebHandler.Run">Run</link>
</seealso>
</element>

<!-- property Visibility: public -->
<element name="TWebHandler.OnLog">
<short>Event for logging web application events and errors</short>
<descr>
<p>Event called when the web application needs to log events or errors.
Allows custom logging implementation for web application diagnostics.</p>
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="TLogEvent">TLogEvent</link>
<link id="TWebHandler.Log">Log</link>
</seealso>
</element>

<!-- property Visibility: public -->
<element name="TWebHandler.OnUnknownRequestEncoding">
<short>Event for handling unknown request content encodings</short>
<descr>
<p>Event called when the HTTP request contains content with an unknown or unsupported encoding.
Allows custom handling of request content encoding issues.</p>
</descr>
<seealso>
</seealso>
</element>

<!-- property Visibility: public -->
<element name="TWebHandler.OnInitModule">
<short>Event for initializing HTTP modules before request processing</short>
<descr>
<p>Event called when an HTTP module is initialized before processing a request.
Allows custom setup and configuration of module properties.</p>
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="TInitModuleEvent">TInitModuleEvent</link>
</seealso>
</element>

<!-- property Visibility: public -->
<element name="TWebHandler.PreferModuleName">
<short>Controls whether module name extraction is preferred over path info parsing</short>
<descr>
<p>When <var>True</var>, the handler prefers extracting module names from path info even when path contains multiple segments.
Affects how module names are determined from request URLs.</p>
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="TWebHandler.GetModuleName">GetModuleName</link>
</seealso>
</element>

<!-- property Visibility: public -->
<element name="TWebHandler.LegacyRouting">
<short>Controls whether to use legacy request routing instead of HTTP router</short>
<descr>
<p>When <var>True</var>, uses the original request routing mechanism instead of the HTTP router system.
Provides backward compatibility with older web applications.</p>
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="TWebHandler.HandleRequest">HandleRequest</link>
</seealso>
</element>

<!-- class Visibility: default -->
<element name="TCustomWebApplication">
<short>Base class for web applications with integrated request handling</short>
<descr>
<p><var>TCustomWebApplication</var> extends <var>TCustomApplication</var> to provide web-specific functionality.
It integrates a <link id="TWebHandler">TWebHandler</link> instance for processing HTTP requests and provides properties for configuring web application behavior.</p>
<p>This class serves as the foundation for all web application implementations including CGI, FastCGI, and other HTTP hosting environments.
It handles application lifecycle, event logging, and web handler management.</p>
</descr>
<errors>
<p>May raise exceptions during web handler initialization or request processing.</p>
</errors>
<seealso>
<link id="TWebHandler">TWebHandler</link>
</seealso>
</element>

<!-- constructor Visibility: public -->
<element name="TCustomWebApplication.Create">
<short>Creates and initializes a new web application instance</short>
<descr>
<p>Creates a new <var>TCustomWebApplication</var> instance and initializes the web handler through the abstract <var>InitializeWebHandler</var> method.
Sets up event handlers for termination and logging.</p>
</descr>
<errors>
<p>May raise exceptions during web handler initialization.</p>
</errors>
<seealso>
<link id="TCustomWebApplication.InitializeWebHandler">InitializeWebHandler</link>
<link id="TCustomWebApplication.Destroy">Destroy</link>
</seealso>
</element>

<!-- argument Visibility: default -->
<element name="TCustomWebApplication.Create.AOwner">
<short>The owner component for the web application</short>
</element>

<!-- destructor Visibility: public -->
<element name="TCustomWebApplication.Destroy">
<short>Destroys the web application and cleans up resources</short>
<descr>
<p>Destroys the web application instance, freeing the web handler and event log resources.
Performs proper cleanup of all web application components.</p>
</descr>
<errors>
<p>No specific errors expected during destruction.</p>
</errors>
<seealso>
<link id="TCustomWebApplication.Create">Create</link>
</seealso>
</element>

<!-- procedure Visibility: public -->
<element name="TCustomWebApplication.CreateForm">
<short>Creates a component instance with the web handler as owner</short>
<descr>
<p>Creates an instance of the specified component class with the web handler as the owner component.
Provides a way to create forms and components within the web application context.</p>
</descr>
<errors>
<p>May raise exceptions during component creation.</p>
</errors>
<seealso>
</seealso>
</element>

<!-- argument Visibility: default -->
<element name="TCustomWebApplication.CreateForm.AClass">
<short>The component class to instantiate</short>
</element>

<!-- argument Visibility: default -->
<element name="TCustomWebApplication.CreateForm.Reference">
<short>Variable to store the created component reference</short>
</element>

<!-- procedure Visibility: public -->
<element name="TCustomWebApplication.Initialize">
<short>Initializes the web application with error handling enabled</short>
<descr>
<p>Initializes the web application and enables <var>StopOnException</var> to ensure proper error handling.
Calls the inherited initialization from <var>TCustomApplication</var>.</p>
</descr>
<errors>
<p>May raise exceptions during application initialization.</p>
</errors>
<seealso>
</seealso>
</element>

<!-- procedure Visibility: public -->
<element name="TCustomWebApplication.Terminate">
<short>Terminates the web application and web handler</short>
<descr>
<p>Terminates the web application by first calling the inherited termination and then terminating the web handler if it's still running.
Ensures clean shutdown of the web request processing loop.</p>
</descr>
<errors>
<p>No specific errors expected during termination.</p>
</errors>
<seealso>
<link id="TWebHandler.Terminate">TWebHandler.Terminate</link>
</seealso>
</element>

<!-- property Visibility: public -->
<element name="TCustomWebApplication.HandleGetOnPost">
<short>Controls whether GET requests are handled by POST handlers</short>
<descr>
<p>Delegates to the <link id="TWebHandler.HandleGetOnPost">TWebHandler.HandleGetOnPost</link> property.
When <var>True</var>, allows POST request handlers to also process GET requests.</p>
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="TWebHandler.HandleGetOnPost">TWebHandler.HandleGetOnPost</link>
</seealso>
</element>

<!-- property Visibility: public -->
<element name="TCustomWebApplication.RedirectOnError">
<short>Controls whether errors trigger HTTP redirects</short>
<descr>
<p>Delegates to the <link id="TWebHandler.RedirectOnError">TWebHandler.RedirectOnError</link> property.
When <var>True</var>, exceptions during request processing cause an HTTP redirect.</p>
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="TWebHandler.RedirectOnError">TWebHandler.RedirectOnError</link>
</seealso>
</element>

<!-- property Visibility: public -->
<element name="TCustomWebApplication.RedirectOnErrorURL">
<short>URL template for error redirects</short>
<descr>
<p>Delegates to the <link id="TWebHandler.RedirectOnErrorURL">TWebHandler.RedirectOnErrorURL</link> property.
Specifies the URL pattern used for error redirects.</p>
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="TWebHandler.RedirectOnErrorURL">TWebHandler.RedirectOnErrorURL</link>
</seealso>
</element>

<!-- property Visibility: public -->
<element name="TCustomWebApplication.ApplicationURL">
<short>Base URL for the web application</short>
<descr>
<p>Delegates to the <link id="TWebHandler.ApplicationURL">TWebHandler.ApplicationURL</link> property.
Specifies the base URL for the web application.</p>
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="TWebHandler.ApplicationURL">TWebHandler.ApplicationURL</link>
</seealso>
</element>

<!-- property Visibility: public -->
<element name="TCustomWebApplication.AllowDefaultModule">
<short>Controls whether requests without module names use default modules</short>
<descr>
<p>Delegates to the <link id="TWebHandler.AllowDefaultModule">TWebHandler.AllowDefaultModule</link> property.
When <var>True</var>, requests without module names use the default module.</p>
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="TWebHandler.AllowDefaultModule">TWebHandler.AllowDefaultModule</link>
</seealso>
</element>

<!-- property Visibility: public -->
<element name="TCustomWebApplication.DefaultModuleName">
<short>Name of the default HTTP module</short>
<descr>
<p>Delegates to the <link id="TWebHandler.DefaultModuleName">TWebHandler.DefaultModuleName</link> property.
Specifies the default HTTP module for requests without explicit module names.</p>
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="TWebHandler.DefaultModuleName">TWebHandler.DefaultModuleName</link>
</seealso>
</element>

<!-- property Visibility: public -->
<element name="TCustomWebApplication.ModuleVariable">
<short>Query parameter name for specifying HTTP module names</short>
<descr>
<p>Delegates to the <link id="TWebHandler.ModuleVariable">TWebHandler.ModuleVariable</link> property.
Specifies the query parameter name used to determine module names.</p>
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="TWebHandler.ModuleVariable">TWebHandler.ModuleVariable</link>
</seealso>
</element>

<!-- property Visibility: public -->
<element name="TCustomWebApplication.OnGetModule">
<short>Event for custom module selection logic</short>
<descr>
<p>Delegates to the <link id="TWebHandler.OnGetModule">TWebHandler.OnGetModule</link> property.
Event called to determine which HTTP module class should handle a request.</p>
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="TWebHandler.OnGetModule">TWebHandler.OnGetModule</link>
</seealso>
</element>

<!-- property Visibility: public -->
<element name="TCustomWebApplication.Email">
<short>Administrator email address for error notifications</short>
<descr>
<p>Delegates to the <link id="TWebHandler.Email">TWebHandler.Email</link> property.
Email address displayed in error pages for user contact.</p>
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="TWebHandler.Email">TWebHandler.Email</link>
</seealso>
</element>

<!-- property Visibility: public -->
<element name="TCustomWebApplication.Administrator">
<short>Administrator name for error pages</short>
<descr>
<p>Delegates to the <link id="TWebHandler.Administrator">TWebHandler.Administrator</link> property.
Name of the application administrator displayed in error pages.</p>
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="TWebHandler.Administrator">TWebHandler.Administrator</link>
</seealso>
</element>

<!-- property Visibility: public -->
<element name="TCustomWebApplication.OnShowRequestException">
<short>Event for custom exception handling during request processing</short>
<descr>
<p>Delegates to the <link id="TWebHandler.OnShowRequestException">TWebHandler.OnShowRequestException</link> property.
Event called when an exception occurs during HTTP request processing.</p>
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="TWebHandler.OnShowRequestException">TWebHandler.OnShowRequestException</link>
</seealso>
</element>

<!-- property Visibility: public -->
<element name="TCustomWebApplication.OnUnknownRequestEncoding">
<short>Event for handling unknown request content encodings</short>
<descr>
<p>Delegates to the <link id="TWebHandler.OnUnknownRequestEncoding">TWebHandler.OnUnknownRequestEncoding</link> property.
Event called when request contains content with unknown encoding.</p>
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="TWebHandler.OnUnknownRequestEncoding">TWebHandler.OnUnknownRequestEncoding</link>
</seealso>
</element>

<!-- property Visibility: public -->
<element name="TCustomWebApplication.EventLog">
<short>Event log instance for logging web application events</short>
<descr>
<p>Provides access to the event log used by the web application for logging events and errors.
The event log is created automatically when first accessed and configured for system logging.</p>
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="TCustomWebApplication.CreateEventLog">CreateEventLog</link>
</seealso>
</element>

<!-- property Visibility: public -->
<element name="TCustomWebApplication.PreferModuleName">
<short>Controls module name extraction preference</short>
<descr>
<p>Delegates to the <link id="TWebHandler.PreferModuleName">TWebHandler.PreferModuleName</link> property.
Controls whether module name extraction is preferred over path info parsing.</p>
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="TWebHandler.PreferModuleName">TWebHandler.PreferModuleName</link>
</seealso>
</element>

<!-- property Visibility: public -->
<element name="TCustomWebApplication.LegacyRouting">
<short>Controls whether to use legacy request routing</short>
<descr>
<p>Delegates to the <link id="TWebHandler.LegacyRouting">TWebHandler.LegacyRouting</link> property.
When <var>True</var>, uses legacy routing instead of the HTTP router system.</p>
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="TWebHandler.LegacyRouting">TWebHandler.LegacyRouting</link>
</seealso>
</element>

<!-- class Visibility: default -->
<element name="EFpWebError">
<short>Exception class for web application errors</short>
<descr>
<p><var>EFpWebError</var> is an exception class specifically for web application errors.
It extends <var>EFPHTTPError</var> to provide HTTP-specific error handling with status codes and status text.</p>
</descr>
<errors>
<p>This class represents errors that occur during web request processing.</p>
</errors>
<seealso>
<link id="TWebHandler.DoError">TWebHandler.DoError</link>
</seealso>
</element>

<!-- procedure Visibility: default -->
<element name="ExceptionToHTML">
<short>Utility function to format exceptions as HTML error pages</short>
<descr>
<p>Formats an exception into a complete HTML error page with stack trace information.
Generates a user-friendly error page that includes exception details, stack trace, and administrator contact information.</p>
<p>The generated HTML includes the application title, error message, stack trace with function names, and optional administrator email contact link.</p>
</descr>
<errors>
<p>No specific errors during HTML generation.</p>
</errors>
<seealso>
<link id="TWebHandler.ShowRequestException">TWebHandler.ShowRequestException</link>
</seealso>
</element>

<!-- argument Visibility: default -->
<element name="ExceptionToHTML.S">
<short>String list to store the generated HTML content</short>
</element>

<!-- argument Visibility: default -->
<element name="ExceptionToHTML.E">
<short>The exception to format as HTML</short>
</element>

<!-- argument Visibility: default -->
<element name="ExceptionToHTML.Title">
<short>Application title for the error page</short>
</element>

<!-- argument Visibility: default -->
<element name="ExceptionToHTML.Email">
<short>Administrator email address for contact link</short>
</element>

<!-- argument Visibility: default -->
<element name="ExceptionToHTML.Administrator">
<short>Administrator name for the contact information</short>
</element>

</module> <!-- custweb -->

</package>
</fpdoc-descriptions>
