<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<fpdoc-descriptions>
<package name="fcl">

<!--
  ====================================================================
    fpjsonapply
  ====================================================================
-->

<module name="fpJsonApply">
<short>Apply elements from one JSON object to another</short>
<descr>
This unit provides the <link id="fpjsonapply.TJSONApplier">TJSONApplier</link> component class for merging JSON objects.
It allows applying (merging) elements from one JSON object to another with various configuration options for ownership control, case sensitivity, type handling, and output formatting.
</descr>

<!-- uses unit Visibility: default -->
<element name="Classes">
<short>Standard component and streaming classes</short>
</element>

<!-- uses unit Visibility: default -->
<element name="SysUtils">
<short>System utility functions and types</short>
</element>

<!-- uses unit Visibility: default -->
<element name="fpJSON">
<short>JSON data structure classes and functions</short>
</element>

<!-- enumeration type Visibility: default -->
<element name="TOwnsJSON">
<short>Enumeration values for JSON object ownership control</short>
<descr>
The <var>TOwnsJSON</var> enumeration defines which JSON objects are owned by the <link id="fpjsonapply.TJSONApplier">TJSONApplier</link> component.
When a JSON object is owned, it will be automatically freed when the component is destroyed or when a new object is assigned.
<dl>
<dt><var>ojSource</var></dt>
<dd>The source JSON object is owned by the applier component</dd>
<dt><var>ojApply</var></dt>
<dd>The apply JSON object is owned by the applier component</dd>
</dl>
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="fpjsonapply.TOwnsJSONs">TOwnsJSONs</link>
<link id="fpjsonapply.TJSONApplier.OwnsJSON">TJSONApplier.OwnsJSON</link>
</seealso>
</element>

<!-- enumeration value Visibility: default -->
<element name="TOwnsJSON.ojSource">
<short>The source JSON object is owned by the applier component</short>
</element>

<!-- enumeration value Visibility: default -->
<element name="TOwnsJSON.ojApply">
<short>The apply JSON object is owned by the applier component</short>
</element>

<!-- set type Visibility: default -->
<element name="TOwnsJSONs">
<short>Set of JSON object ownership flags</short>
<descr>
The <var>TOwnsJSONs</var> type is a set of <link id="fpjsonapply.TOwnsJSON">TOwnsJSON</link> enumeration values.
It specifies which JSON objects are owned and managed by the <link id="fpjsonapply.TJSONApplier">TJSONApplier</link> component.
Owned objects will be automatically freed when no longer needed.
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="fpjsonapply.TOwnsJSON">TOwnsJSON</link>
<link id="fpjsonapply.TJSONApplier.OwnsJSON">TJSONApplier.OwnsJSON</link>
</seealso>
</element>

<!-- class Visibility: default -->
<element name="TJSONApplier">
<short>Component class for applying (merging) JSON objects</short>
<descr>
The <var>TJSONApplier</var> class is a component that provides functionality to apply (merge) elements from one JSON object to another.
It supports loading JSON objects from files or working with existing objects in memory, with various configuration options for controlling the merge behavior.
The component can merge at specific paths within JSON structures, handle type conflicts, control case sensitivity, and manage object ownership.
</descr>
<errors>
Raises <var>EJSON</var> exceptions when:
<ul>
<li>Source or apply JSON objects are empty</li>
<li>JSON files do not contain valid JSON objects</li>
<li>Specified paths are not found in the JSON structures</li>
</ul>
</errors>
<seealso>
<link id="fpjsonapply.TOwnsJSON">TOwnsJSON</link>
<link id="fpjsonapply.TOwnsJSONs">TOwnsJSONs</link>
</seealso>
</element>

<!-- destructor Visibility: public -->
<element name="TJSONApplier.destroy">
<short>Destructor that frees owned JSON objects and cleans up resources</short>
<descr>
The <var>destroy</var> destructor frees any JSON objects that are owned by the component as indicated by the <link id="fpjsonapply.TJSONApplier.OwnsJSON">OwnsJSON</link> property.
It also frees the destination JSON object if it differs from the source JSON object.
</descr>
<errors>
</errors>
<seealso>
<link id="fpjsonapply.TJSONApplier.OwnsJSON">TJSONApplier.OwnsJSON</link>
<link id="fpjsonapply.TJSONApplier.SourceJSON">TJSONApplier.SourceJSON</link>
<link id="fpjsonapply.TJSONApplier.ApplyJSON">TJSONApplier.ApplyJSON</link>
<link id="fpjsonapply.TJSONApplier.DestJSON">TJSONApplier.DestJSON</link>
</seealso>
</element>

<!-- procedure Visibility: public -->
<element name="TJSONApplier.Execute">
<short>Executes the JSON merge operation from apply JSON to source JSON</short>
<descr>
The <var>Execute</var> method performs the main JSON merge operation.
It loads the source and apply JSON objects from files if they are not already set, then applies the elements from the apply JSON object to the source JSON object.
The result is stored in the <link id="fpjsonapply.TJSONApplier.DestJSON">DestJSON</link> property.
If file paths are specified, it starts merging at those specific locations within the JSON structures.
If a destination filename is specified, the result is automatically saved to that file.
</descr>
<errors>
Raises <var>EJSON</var> exceptions when:
<ul>
<li>Source JSON object is empty</li>
<li>Apply JSON object is empty</li>
<li>JSON files do not contain valid JSON objects</li>
<li>Specified source or apply paths are not found or do not point to JSON objects</li>
</ul>
</errors>
<seealso>
<link id="fpjsonapply.TJSONApplier.SourceJSON">TJSONApplier.SourceJSON</link>
<link id="fpjsonapply.TJSONApplier.ApplyJSON">TJSONApplier.ApplyJSON</link>
<link id="fpjsonapply.TJSONApplier.DestJSON">TJSONApplier.DestJSON</link>
<link id="fpjsonapply.TJSONApplier.SourcePath">TJSONApplier.SourcePath</link>
<link id="fpjsonapply.TJSONApplier.ApplyPath">TJSONApplier.ApplyPath</link>
</seealso>
</element>

<!-- property Visibility: public -->
<element name="TJSONApplier.SourceJSON">
<short>Source JSON object to merge into</short>
<descr>
The <var>SourceJSON</var> property holds the source JSON object that serves as the base for the merge operation.
If not set directly, it will be loaded automatically from the file specified in <link id="fpjsonapply.TJSONApplier.SourceFileName">SourceFileName</link> when <link id="fpjsonapply.TJSONApplier.Execute">Execute</link> is called.
When a new value is assigned, any previously owned source JSON object is freed.
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="fpjsonapply.TJSONApplier.SourceFileName">TJSONApplier.SourceFileName</link>
<link id="fpjsonapply.TJSONApplier.DestJSON">TJSONApplier.DestJSON</link>
<link id="fpjsonapply.TJSONApplier.OwnsJSON">TJSONApplier.OwnsJSON</link>
</seealso>
</element>

<!-- property Visibility: public -->
<element name="TJSONApplier.ApplyJSON">
<short>JSON object containing elements to apply to the source</short>
<descr>
The <var>ApplyJSON</var> property holds the JSON object whose elements will be merged into the source JSON object.
If not set directly, it will be loaded automatically from the file specified in <link id="fpjsonapply.TJSONApplier.ApplyFileName">ApplyFileName</link> when <link id="fpjsonapply.TJSONApplier.Execute">Execute</link> is called.
When a new value is assigned, any previously owned apply JSON object is freed.
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="fpjsonapply.TJSONApplier.ApplyFileName">TJSONApplier.ApplyFileName</link>
<link id="fpjsonapply.TJSONApplier.SourceJSON">TJSONApplier.SourceJSON</link>
<link id="fpjsonapply.TJSONApplier.OwnsJSON">TJSONApplier.OwnsJSON</link>
</seealso>
</element>

<!-- property Visibility: public -->
<element name="TJSONApplier.DestJSON">
<short>Destination JSON object containing the merge result</short>
<descr>
The <var>DestJSON</var> property contains the result of the merge operation after <link id="fpjsonapply.TJSONApplier.Execute">Execute</link> is called.
If <link id="fpjsonapply.TJSONApplier.CloneSource">CloneSource</link> is <var>True</var>, this will be a clone of the source JSON object.
If <link id="fpjsonapply.TJSONApplier.CloneSource">CloneSource</link> is <var>False</var>, this will be the same reference as the source JSON object.
This property is read-only and is set automatically during the merge operation.
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="fpjsonapply.TJSONApplier.SourceJSON">TJSONApplier.SourceJSON</link>
<link id="fpjsonapply.TJSONApplier.CloneSource">TJSONApplier.CloneSource</link>
<link id="fpjsonapply.TJSONApplier.Execute">TJSONApplier.Execute</link>
</seealso>
</element>

<!-- property Visibility: public -->
<element name="TJSONApplier.OwnsJSON">
<short>Set specifying which JSON objects are owned by the component</short>
<descr>
The <var>OwnsJSON</var> property is a set of <link id="fpjsonapply.TOwnsJSON">TOwnsJSON</link> values that specifies which JSON objects are owned and managed by the component.
Owned objects are automatically freed when the component is destroyed or when new objects are assigned.
This property is automatically updated when JSON objects are loaded from files.
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="fpjsonapply.TOwnsJSON">TOwnsJSON</link>
<link id="fpjsonapply.TOwnsJSONs">TOwnsJSONs</link>
<link id="fpjsonapply.TJSONApplier.SourceJSON">TJSONApplier.SourceJSON</link>
<link id="fpjsonapply.TJSONApplier.ApplyJSON">TJSONApplier.ApplyJSON</link>
</seealso>
</element>

<!-- property Visibility: published -->
<element name="TJSONApplier.SourceFileName">
<short>Filename to load source JSON from if SourceJSON is not set</short>
<descr>
The <var>SourceFileName</var> property specifies the file path from which to load the source JSON object.
If <link id="fpjsonapply.TJSONApplier.SourceJSON">SourceJSON</link> is not set when <link id="fpjsonapply.TJSONApplier.Execute">Execute</link> is called, the JSON object will be loaded from this file.
When loaded from file, the component will take ownership of the JSON object.
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="fpjsonapply.TJSONApplier.SourceJSON">TJSONApplier.SourceJSON</link>
<link id="fpjsonapply.TJSONApplier.OwnsJSON">TJSONApplier.OwnsJSON</link>
<link id="fpjsonapply.TJSONApplier.Execute">TJSONApplier.Execute</link>
</seealso>
</element>

<!-- property Visibility: published -->
<element name="TJSONApplier.SourcePath">
<short>JSON path in source object where merging should start</short>
<descr>
The <var>SourcePath</var> property specifies a JSON path within the source JSON object where the merge operation should begin.
If empty, merging starts at the root of the source object.
The path must point to an existing JSON object within the source structure.
JSON paths use dot notation to navigate nested objects.
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="fpjsonapply.TJSONApplier.SourceJSON">TJSONApplier.SourceJSON</link>
<link id="fpjsonapply.TJSONApplier.ApplyPath">TJSONApplier.ApplyPath</link>
<link id="fpjsonapply.TJSONApplier.Execute">TJSONApplier.Execute</link>
</seealso>
</element>

<!-- property Visibility: published -->
<element name="TJSONApplier.ApplyFileName">
<short>Filename to load apply JSON from if ApplyJSON is not set</short>
<descr>
The <var>ApplyFileName</var> property specifies the file path from which to load the apply JSON object.
If <link id="fpjsonapply.TJSONApplier.ApplyJSON">ApplyJSON</link> is not set when <link id="fpjsonapply.TJSONApplier.Execute">Execute</link> is called, the JSON object will be loaded from this file.
When loaded from file, the component will take ownership of the JSON object.
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="fpjsonapply.TJSONApplier.ApplyJSON">TJSONApplier.ApplyJSON</link>
<link id="fpjsonapply.TJSONApplier.OwnsJSON">TJSONApplier.OwnsJSON</link>
<link id="fpjsonapply.TJSONApplier.Execute">TJSONApplier.Execute</link>
</seealso>
</element>

<!-- property Visibility: published -->
<element name="TJSONApplier.ApplyPath">
<short>JSON path in apply object where merging data should be taken from</short>
<descr>
The <var>ApplyPath</var> property specifies a JSON path within the apply JSON object from which elements should be merged.
If empty, elements are taken from the root of the apply object.
The path must point to an existing JSON object within the apply structure.
JSON paths use dot notation to navigate nested objects.
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="fpjsonapply.TJSONApplier.ApplyJSON">TJSONApplier.ApplyJSON</link>
<link id="fpjsonapply.TJSONApplier.SourcePath">TJSONApplier.SourcePath</link>
<link id="fpjsonapply.TJSONApplier.Execute">TJSONApplier.Execute</link>
</seealso>
</element>

<!-- property Visibility: published -->
<element name="TJSONApplier.DestFileName">
<short>Filename to write the destination JSON to after merging</short>
<descr>
The <var>DestFileName</var> property specifies the file path where the result of the merge operation should be saved.
If this property is set, the destination JSON object will be automatically saved to this file after <link id="fpjsonapply.TJSONApplier.Execute">Execute</link> completes.
If empty, no automatic saving is performed.
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="fpjsonapply.TJSONApplier.DestJSON">TJSONApplier.DestJSON</link>
<link id="fpjsonapply.TJSONApplier.Execute">TJSONApplier.Execute</link>
<link id="fpjsonapply.TJSONApplier.Formatted">TJSONApplier.Formatted</link>
</seealso>
</element>

<!-- property Visibility: published -->
<element name="TJSONApplier.CloneSource">
<short>Controls whether to make a clone copy of source JSON before applying changes</short>
<descr>
The <var>CloneSource</var> property determines whether a clone copy of the source JSON object is made before applying changes.
When <var>True</var>, the source JSON object is cloned and changes are applied to the clone, leaving the original unchanged.
When <var>False</var>, changes are applied directly to the source JSON object.
The default value is <var>False</var>.
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="fpjsonapply.TJSONApplier.SourceJSON">TJSONApplier.SourceJSON</link>
<link id="fpjsonapply.TJSONApplier.DestJSON">TJSONApplier.DestJSON</link>
<link id="fpjsonapply.TJSONApplier.Execute">TJSONApplier.Execute</link>
</seealso>
</element>

<!-- property Visibility: published -->
<element name="TJSONApplier.CaseInsensitive">
<short>Controls whether property name matching is case sensitive</short>
<descr>
The <var>CaseInsensitive</var> property controls whether property names are matched case-sensitively during the merge operation.
When <var>True</var>, property names are compared ignoring case differences.
When <var>False</var>, property names must match exactly including case.
The default value is <var>False</var>.
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="fpjsonapply.TJSONApplier.Execute">TJSONApplier.Execute</link>
<link id="fpjsonapply.TJSONApplier.RemoveNonExisting">TJSONApplier.RemoveNonExisting</link>
</seealso>
</element>

<!-- property Visibility: published -->
<element name="TJSONApplier.ForceCorrectType">
<short>Controls whether to overwrite properties when types differ between source and apply JSON</short>
<descr>
The <var>ForceCorrectType</var> property determines the behavior when a property exists in both source and apply JSON objects but with different data types.
When <var>True</var>, the property in the source is deleted and replaced with the property from the apply JSON.
When <var>False</var>, properties with different types are handled according to their specific types (objects are merged recursively).
The default value is <var>False</var>.
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="fpjsonapply.TJSONApplier.Execute">TJSONApplier.Execute</link>
<link id="fpjsonapply.TJSONApplier.CaseInsensitive">TJSONApplier.CaseInsensitive</link>
</seealso>
</element>

<!-- property Visibility: published -->
<element name="TJSONApplier.RemoveNonExisting">
<short>Controls whether to remove properties from source that do not exist in apply JSON</short>
<descr>
The <var>RemoveNonExisting</var> property determines whether properties that exist in the source JSON but not in the apply JSON should be removed after merging.
When <var>True</var>, properties in the source that are not present in the apply JSON are deleted.
When <var>False</var>, existing properties in the source are preserved even if they do not exist in the apply JSON.
The default value is <var>False</var>.
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="fpjsonapply.TJSONApplier.Execute">TJSONApplier.Execute</link>
<link id="fpjsonapply.TJSONApplier.CaseInsensitive">TJSONApplier.CaseInsensitive</link>
</seealso>
</element>

<!-- property Visibility: published -->
<element name="TJSONApplier.Formatted">
<short>Controls whether output JSON is formatted with indentation and line breaks</short>
<descr>
The <var>Formatted</var> property controls whether the JSON output is formatted with indentation and line breaks for better readability.
When <var>True</var>, the output JSON is formatted with proper indentation.
When <var>False</var>, the output JSON is written as a compact string without formatting.
This property affects the output when writing to the <link id="fpjsonapply.TJSONApplier.DestFileName">DestFileName</link>.
The default value is <var>False</var>.
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="fpjsonapply.TJSONApplier.DestFileName">TJSONApplier.DestFileName</link>
<link id="fpjsonapply.TJSONApplier.Execute">TJSONApplier.Execute</link>
</seealso>
</element>

</module> <!-- fpjsonapply -->

</package>
</fpdoc-descriptions>
