<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<fpdoc-descriptions>
<package name="fcl">

<!--
  ====================================================================
    json2yaml
  ====================================================================
-->

<module name="Json2Yaml">
<short>JSON to YAML converter unit</short>
<descr>
<p>This unit provides functionality to convert JSON data structures into YAML format.
It implements the <link id="json2yaml.TJSONToYaml">TJSONToYaml</link> class which can convert
any JSON data type (objects, arrays, strings, numbers, booleans, and null values) into
equivalent YAML representation with proper indentation and formatting.</p>
</descr>

<!-- uses unit Visibility: default -->
<element name="classes">
<short>Standard stream and component classes</short>
</element>

<!-- uses unit Visibility: default -->
<element name="fpjson">
<short>JSON data manipulation classes and types</short>
</element>

<!-- class Visibility: default -->
<element name="TJSONToYaml">
<short>Class for converting JSON data to YAML format</short>
<descr>
<p><var>TJSONToYaml</var> provides functionality to convert JSON data structures into YAML format.
The class can handle all JSON data types including objects, arrays, strings, numbers, booleans, and null values.
The conversion preserves the hierarchical structure and produces properly indented YAML output.</p>

<p>The class supports configurable indentation size and can optionally add a YAML document header (---).
Conversion is performed by calling the <link id="json2yaml.TJSONToYaml.Convert">Convert</link> method with
the source JSON data and target output stream.</p>
</descr>
<errors>
</errors>
<seealso>
<link id="json2yaml.TJSONToYaml.Convert">Convert</link>
<link id="json2yaml.TJSONToYaml.AddHeader">AddHeader</link>
<link id="json2yaml.TJSONToYaml.IndentSize">IndentSize</link>
</seealso>
</element>

<!-- procedure Visibility: public -->
<element name="TJSONToYaml.Convert">
<short>Convert JSON data to YAML format</short>
<descr>
<p>The <var>Convert</var> method converts the provided JSON data structure to YAML format
and writes the result to the specified output stream. The method handles all JSON data types:
objects, arrays, strings, numbers, booleans, and null values.</p>

<p>The conversion process uses the current <link id="json2yaml.TJSONToYaml.IndentSize">IndentSize</link>
setting for proper YAML indentation. If <link id="json2yaml.TJSONToYaml.AddHeader">AddHeader</link>
is <var>True</var>, a YAML document separator (---) is written at the beginning of the output.</p>

<p>Objects are converted to YAML mappings with key-value pairs, arrays become YAML sequences
with list items prefixed by dashes, and scalar values are converted to their string representations.</p>
</descr>
<errors>
</errors>
<seealso>
<link id="json2yaml.TJSONToYaml.AddHeader">AddHeader</link>
<link id="json2yaml.TJSONToYaml.IndentSize">IndentSize</link>
</seealso>
</element>

<!-- argument Visibility: default -->
<element name="TJSONToYaml.Convert.JSON">
<short>Source JSON data to convert</short>
</element>

<!-- argument Visibility: default -->
<element name="TJSONToYaml.Convert.aOutput">
<short>Target stream for YAML output</short>
</element>

<!-- property Visibility: public -->
<element name="TJSONToYaml.AddHeader">
<short>Controls whether to add YAML document header</short>
<descr>
<p>The <var>AddHeader</var> property determines whether a YAML document separator (---) is
written at the beginning of the converted output. When set to <var>True</var>, the YAML document
header is added before the actual content. When <var>False</var>, only the converted JSON content
is written to the output stream.</p>

<p>The YAML document separator is part of the YAML specification and indicates the start of
a YAML document, which can be useful when multiple YAML documents are concatenated or when
strict YAML compliance is required.</p>
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="json2yaml.TJSONToYaml.Convert">Convert</link>
</seealso>
</element>

<!-- property Visibility: public -->
<element name="TJSONToYaml.IndentSize">
<short>Number of spaces used for indentation</short>
<descr>
<p>The <var>IndentSize</var> property specifies the number of spaces used for each level of
indentation in the generated YAML output. This value controls the visual structure and
readability of the converted YAML document.</p>

<p>If not explicitly set, the default indentation size of 2 spaces is used during conversion.
The indentation is applied consistently throughout the document to maintain proper YAML
structure for nested objects and arrays.</p>
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="json2yaml.TJSONToYaml.Convert">Convert</link>
</seealso>
</element>

</module> <!-- json2yaml -->

</package>
</fpdoc-descriptions>
